# 哈喽大家好我是王刚
Hello everyone, this is Wang Gang
# 本期视频我给大家分享如何
In today's video, I'll share the recipe for
# 精炼猪油
Refining pork fat
# 首先我们准备一副猪板油大约2500克左右
First, we prepare around 2500g of lard
# 通常来说猪越大板油则越多
A fatter pig will have a bigger piece of lard
# 然后小心地剔除多余的瘦肉和隐藏在边上的淋巴
Then we carefully remove the extra meat and the hidden lymph on the side
# 去除杂质和淋巴之后将猪油切成小块备用
After removing the extra parts, cut the lard into small pieces and set them aside
# 同学们大约切成麻将大小即可
The size of a Mahjong card will be good enough
# 下一步开始准备辅料
Now let's prepare the minor ingredients
# 准备半斤大葱切成小段备用
Prepare 250g of green onions and cut them into shorter pieces
# 准备2大块生姜切成姜片备用（约150克）
Prepare two pieces of ginger and slice them (around 150g)
# 同学们姜葱是用于炼猪油时加入增香去除异味
Ginger and green onion adds extra flavor and removes the bad taste
# 最后我们准备瓦罐器具1个
Now we prepare a jug
# 加入适量的食用盐（约3克）
Add 3g of salt
# 再加入适量的青花椒
Then add some green Sichuan peppercorn
# 这一步的目的是延长猪油装在里面的保质期
This is to let the pork fat last longer
# 下一步开始制作
Now start preparing the pork fat
# 首先我们在锅中加入适量的清水
First add some water to the wok
# 然后加入切好的猪油首次焯水1分钟
THen add the cutted lard to parboil for a minute
# 同学们时间的计算方法必须是水开之后的1分钟
This means a minute after the water boils
# 这一步的目的是去除板油中的血渍和杂质
This is to remove the blood and impurities from the lard
# 1分钟之后捞出备用
Take it out after a minute
# 然后锅中重新加入适量的清水
Then add some water to the wok again
# 再次将猪油下锅焯水1分钟
And parboil for another minute
# 中途加入适量的料酒去腥
Add some Chinese cooking wine midway to remove the bad taste
# 这一步可以有效的去除板油的异味
This is helpful to remove the bad smell
# 焯水1分钟之后捞出备用
Parboil for a minute and take it out
# 下一步开始炼(猪)油
Now let's refine the pork fat
# 锅洗干净之后加入1碗纯净水
Rinse the wok and add a bowl of water
# 然后将猪油下锅转中小火炼10分钟
Add the pork fat and turn to medium-low heat for 10 minutes
# 此过程分为3个阶段
This process has three stages
# 第一阶段是前3分钟
The first lasts for 3 minutes
# 这一步是去除猪油中的水份
This is to remove the water from the fat
# 所以此时会有大量的水份蒸发锅中冒白烟
So now you'll see lots of water vapour
# 同学们锅里面的油脂此时是乳白色
And the fat should be milky white in the wok
# 第二阶段是6分钟之后锅中的蒸汽明显减少
The second stage is 6 minutes after we start, you see less steam
# 然后锅中的油脂逐渐变成透明色
Then the fat also turns transparent in the wok
# 在第二阶段也就是熬制6分钟之后加入切好的姜葱下锅
Now, meaning 6 minutes after we start, add cutted gingers and green onions
# 此时开始进入第三阶段出油增香
Now we enter the third stage in which the oil comes out and we start to smell it
# 熬制9分钟油渣和姜葱会变成金黄色（油脂明亮）
After 9 minutes, gingers, green onions, and the crispy fat all turns golden (the fat looks bright)
# 然后将油脂取出放入装有盐和花椒的器具中
Then we pour the fat out to the jar with salt and peppercorn
# 剩余的油渣我们继续小火熬1分钟
We continue to heat the remaining crispy fat on low heat for a minute
# 1分钟之后将油渣倒出挤干油水即可
After a minute, take it out and get rid of the oil
# 同学们此时的油渣可以撒上白糖直接吃
Now we can eat it with some sugar
# 也可以用于炒蔬菜或者炖汤
Or use it to stir-fry vegetables or make soups
# 熬制好的猪油待冷却之后即可保存
We wait until the pork fat cools down to store it
# 下面开始技术总结
# 第一，熬制猪油必须小火否则很容易老
# 第二，猪油的吸附力比植物油更强所以炒蔬菜会更香
# 第三，猪油常温保存最好不超过90天
# 炼猪油的技术总结完毕
Now we summarize the key tips
First of all, we need to use low heat
Secondly, compared to vegetable oil, pork fat tastes better with stir-fried vegetables because it can be better absorbed
Thirdly, you'd better finish the pork fat within 90 days if it's kept under room temperature
Above is all for Refined Pork Fat